视频字幕由 SSK字幕组 制作发布
字幕只供学习 请勿做任何商业行为
敬请关注新浪微博@SSK字幕组
翻译： bezero 酥酥 豆沙包 强妹 爱吃 brian
校对：慕斯
后期：D
时间轴：阿黎
女子
监狱
第二季第二集
总监：慕斯
想听我唱歌么
Wanna hear my song?
嗨 我是布里乔
Hi, I'm Brichelle.
-你好 -你好么
- Hello. - How are you?
布里乔 你特么的给我滚开
Brichelle! You back the fuck off!
你知道么 她先天自控力有缺陷
She got impulse-control issues, you know?
我很聪明 我能背全元素周期表
I'm real smart. I know the whole periodic chart.
我爱科学
I love science!
好吧 塔莎 我们给你买个冰沙好么
Okay, Tasha, how about we get you a shaved ice, yes?
你喜欢什么味的
What flavor would you like?
-但是 我 -塔莎
- But I was... - Tasha.
蓝色的
Blue.
好劣质的冰沙
That looks vile.
它是蓝色的 尝起来却像红色的
It look blue, but it tastes like red.
蓝色和红色只是颜色 亲爱的 不是味道
Blue and red are colors, darlin'. They're not flavors.
好吧 可是很美味 我喜欢美味的东西
Well, it's tasty. I like me somethin' tasty.
特别是在今天这种日子里
Especially on days like now.
人们只喜欢小宝宝
People only want the babies.
人们当然只喜欢小宝宝 小宝宝萌萌哒
Of course they want the babies. Babies are cute.
我也很萌啊
I'm cute.
不 你是大孩子 而且你的头发乱如马草
No, you're big, and your hair's ratsy.
你心浮气躁长得黑
And you're too eager and too dark.
现在你的嘴巴还是蓝的 不过我猜味道应该像红的
And now your mouth is blue, but I suppose it tastes like red.
你真讨厌
You nasty.
不 不
Mmm-hmm.
我只是实话实说 亲爱的
I just call 'em like I see 'em, darlin'.
你的孤儿院在这附近么
Your group home in this neighborhood?
你怎么知道我住孤儿院
How you know I live in a group home?
好孩子 这就是我生活中的光明
My dear boy, this feels light to me.
如果你不想睡大街最好总让我感到阳光明媚
Light ain't right unless you like sleeping on the street.
呐 这不是光 这是一大笔钱
Nah, it ain't light. It's just big bills.
好吧 那么 我们晚餐见 宝贝
Well, then, I'll see you at home for dinner, baby.
噢 妈蛋 你是个蛇头
Aw, shit, you a connect.
我是女白领
I'm a businesswoman.
我刚刚无意听到了你吹你的科学才能
I couldn't help hear you braggin' on your science back there.
印象深刻啊
I'm impressed.
我还知道π
I also know pi.
你个小蠢蛋还知道派么
Your ass tells me you know pie.
是数学的π 不是馅饼的派
Pi. Not "Pie".
我可以背到小数点后56位
Up to 56 digits.
你愿意学赚钱么
You care to learn the trade?
开玩笑 没有蛇头怎么学
Hell, no, not with no connect.
我有麻烦了 我找不到长久的寄居家庭
I get in trouble, I never find a forever family.
你也许可以考虑一下
You might wanna start thinkin'
自己去争取一个长久的寄居家庭 美味妞
about making your own forever family, Taystee.
在这干等 等死也等不来
You wait around for one to come along, you might die waitin'.
我叫塔莎
My name is Tasha.
我知道 但是我觉得美味妞更适合你
Yeah, but Taystee suits you somehow.
就像你说的 人人都喜欢美味
Like you said, everybody like a little somethin' tasty.
我会继续注意你的 美味妞
I'll be keepin' my eye on you, Taystee Girl.
我们会再见的
See you around the way.
这个真美
This is sweet!
哟 要不是要求职业装 穿上这个我会嗨翻全场
Yo, I'd rock this if I wasn't being all professional.
你穿啊 你知道这不过是走过场
Why you care? You know it's all bullshit.
是不是走过场我都要赢
Bullshit or no, I wanna win!
姑娘们 我们的目的是要创造良好的第一印象
Ladies, it's about making a good first impression.
你这有白色的衣服么
You got anything in white?
我妈妈总说白色适合我
My mother always said that was my color.
恶 这衣服上散发着每个穿过它的女囚的味道
Ugh! I mean, you could smell every inmate that's ever worn this.
你是不是从没洗过
You ever wash this shit?
你为大号女人准备了衣服么 又大又美的那种
You got something for the larger woman? Big and beautiful?
最里头有加大号的
We have plus size on the end there.
噢 妈蛋 我不想穿麻袋
Aw, shit. Man, I don't wanna wear no sack.
我有曲线的 我可是超性感的
I got curves. I'm a plushious woman.
如果我们真是要打扮的职业
If this is really about career dressing for us,
不应该穿麦当劳工作服或者女仆装之类的吗
shouldn't this be all, like, McDonald's and maids' uniforms?
不 你得大胆想
No! Do not think small.
我们是为了梦寐以求的事业而精心装扮
We are dressing ourselves for the career that we want.
你得有全方位的想法 力求获取面试机会
You have to put it into the universe, dress for success.
穿豹纹吧
Take the leopard.
嗷 我刚没看见豹纹 噢 真美
Oh, I didn't see the leopard! Ooh, that's cute.
如果我想做一个 比如 海洋生物学家
What if I wanna be, like, a marine biologist?
要穿潜水服么
You got a wet suit?
如果你想应聘做一个海洋生物学家
If you want to apply for a job in marine biology,
你可能得去相关部门参加面试
you might have to go to an office for an interview.
-哈 -这件怎么样
- Ha! - What about this?
桃色系很配你的肤色
The peach tones would look so good with your skin.
有人能帮我拉个拉链么 谢谢了
Could somebody help zip me, please?
我感觉拉不上诶
I don't think that's gonna work.
你是说我很肥么
You callin' me fat?
不 我只是说你很 嗯 肩略宽
No. I'm just saying that you're... yeah, you're broad.
哪里都宽 丰乳肥臀
You're like a broad broad.
她确实略宽
She a broad somethin.'
你也确实略婊
And you a bitch somethin.'
我要从这边开始收了
I'm gonna pull in this side here.
-小心点 小心 -你从那边收
- Careful. Careful. - And you pull in that side.
来个人帮她拉拉链
And someone's gotta get the zipper.
-好了 来吧 -好
- Okay, we can do this. - Okay.
我来拉拉链 开始吧 收腹啊 妹子
I'll do the zipper. Let's go. Suck it in, girl.
我收了
I am sucking.
艹
Fuck.
噢 很好
Oh, God.
好看么
How's it look?
我不想和你一起出去
Like I don't wanna be anywhere near you
免得看到你身上那些珠子蹦到别人脸上
when those beads pop off and shoot people in the face.
我有点好奇
Out of curiosity,
你穿这件是要做什么工作捏
what kind of job were you thinking of gettin' in that?
我只是来走秀的
I'm just here playin' dress-up.
姑娘们 你们最好快点
Ladies, you better get movin.'
我们十分钟后就去教堂
We're walkin' over to that chapel in 10 minutes.
我还没找到合适的
I don't have anything.
嘿 我能问问你么
Hey, can I ask you something?
如果是你 你面试时会穿什么
What would you wear if you were going to a job interview
比如去一个犹他州的医药公司应聘
at a medical supply company in Utica?
只是假设
Just hypothetically speaking.
凭什么弗拉卡能去模拟招聘会而我们却要留在这
How come Flaca gets to do job fair and we're stuck here?
因为弗拉卡先报名
'Cause Flaca asked first,
而且如果所有人都去了这里就没人了
and if I let everybody go, nobody would be here.
下次还想去就早点报名
Next time, ask first.
她根本没必要去模拟招聘会
She don't even need job fair.
他男票是个茉莉国王
Her boyfriend's like the king of molly.
所有纽约的泡吧孩子都是他的顾客
He be selling to every club kid in New York.
可惜吹了
That shit is blowing up.
什么是茉莉
What's molly?
摇头丸纯粉
The pure powder form of MDMA.
说是带给你纯净的享受
Supposed to be like a clean ecstasy,
可却磨坏了我的牙
but it made me grind my teeth.
你怎么不坐牢呢 塔斯基吉
How come you ain't in jail, Luschek?
我在牢里啊 特么每天都在
I am in jail, every fuckin' day.
暖气是想开着还是关上
You want the radiator on or off?
关上 这里够热了
Off. It's hot enough in here.
可除了这里都冻死人了
And freezing everywhere else.
我们厕所的管子又冻上了 你去修修怎么样
The pipes in our bathroom froze again, how about deal with that?
我又不是水管工
I'm not a plumber.
噢 我们搞错了 你总是露半个屁股 所以我们以为
Oh, our mistake, you got that whole ass-crack thing going, so...
犯人 你想要我给你个道歉的机会么
Inmate, you want me to give you a shot?
嘿 尝一个为招聘会做的蛋糕吧
Hey, have a job fair brownie.
玛利亚 闭上你的大嘴巴 赶紧洗盘子
Maria, stop running your mouth and run the dishwasher.
达亚 文 我有东西给你
Daya? Ven, I've got something for you.
谢天谢地 我都快死了
Thank God. I'm dying.
这个有用么
Is this gonna work?
会有用的 喝了吧 妹妹
It should. Drink up, mami.
你给她喝了什么
What are you giving her over there?
没什么
It's nothing.
是帮助她排便的 她便秘了
It's to help her poop. She's backed up.
你怎么不告诉我
Why didn't you tell me?
-你不会想听我便便的事的 -我当然想听
- You don't wanna hear about my bathroom. - Of course I do.
好吧 阿莱达
Okay, Aleida.
我便秘5天了 开心了么
I haven't shit for five days, you happy?
恶
Ugh!
谢谢你了 格洛丽亚
Thank you, Gloria.
你认为你在干嘛
What do you think you're doing?
噢 伙计 放轻松
Oh, man, relax.
那只是西梅汁加橄榄油 治疗便秘的小魔法
It's prune juice, olive oil, a little magic.
不会伤害你的小宝贝的
It's not gonna hurt the baby.
你不是她妈妈，我才是她妈妈
You're not her mother, I'm her mother.
我想你现在看起来更像她阿姨
I think right now you're more like her aunt.
噢 噢 不
Uh-uh, no.
我只是没有
I didn't get me a belly
肚子上长满妊娠纹罢了
full of stretch marks to be no fucking tía.
听着 别紧张 她来找我 我帮助她
Look, relax, she came to me, I helped her out.
她和我相处感觉很舒服
She's comfortable with me.
是啊 能有多舒服
Yeah, too comfortable.
言归正传 你们也看到了
So, as you can see, we have a
我们专门安排了几天精彩的活动
very exciting few days planned for all of you.
现在活动开始 首先是获取面试的职业装
And now to start things off, here from Dress for Success,
为你们提供一些
to give you some dos and
面试着装的技巧和禁忌 赛金太太
don'ts of interview dressing, Mrs. Sackin.
谢谢你
Thank you.
通往成功之路 着装为第一要素
Dress for Success is the premier
这是当今失业女性重返职场的首要因素
support network for today's unemployed woman.
现在开始吧 姑娘们
Let us begin our journey. Ladies?
噢
Oh!
好的 现在 我们来看看
Okay, right away, what do we see?
鸡尾酒礼服是不适合面试的
That a cocktail dress is not proper interview attire.
绝不是职业装 日常出门都不会这么穿
This is not corporate or even daytime wear.
-就是就是 -一点也不专业
- Nope. - Wholly unprofessional.
我只是想秀秀身材
I'm just showing off my assets.
接下来 我们看到的豹纹女和水手妹
Next, I'm going to say leopard, little sailor girl,
还有这位粉红小妹
and our friend in peach here
她们的穿着都不适合面试
are also not properly attired for an interview.
动物标记太狂野 容易留下不好的印象
The animal print is too racy and implies poor judgment,
水手装太幼稚
and the sailor outfit is childish.
-公司要招的是成年人 -成年人
- Companies are looking to hire adults. - Adults.
最后 桃色只是很不合适
And finally, the peach is simply ill-fitting,
过时 不够讨巧
dated, and not flattering.
-但是是你叫我穿这件的啊 -是的是你说的
- But you told me to wear it. - Yeah, you did.
我只是想和海豚游泳
I just wanna swim with dolphins.
谢谢 你们可以下台了
Thank you, you can leave the stage now.
好啦 我们再看看接下来几位
Okay, let's look at what's going right up here.
不错的面试装哦
This is a good interview outfit.
很适合她
It fits her well.
黑丝袜代表一丝保守 完美风华
The dark stockings give it a conservative, polished finish.
但是哥特式彩妆太浓
I believe the makeup is a bit gothic and heavy-handed,
不过整体效果挺耐看的
but overall the look is solid.
没错 耐看
That's right, solid.
另一套装扮是套装和衬衫
Another strong ensemble we have is the pantsuit and blouse.
很经典
It's classic.
不过 我们也遇到了一些
However, we do run into some
严重的个人仪表问题
serious problems with personal grooming here.
嗯
Huh?
头发 忒乱了 毛糙糙的 不够整洁
The hair, it's messy, unpolished, unkempt.
-我的头发很干净的好吧 -散乱 就像一堆杂草
- My hair is clean. - It's wild and slovenly.
很抱歉我不严肃不无聊
I'm sorry it's not uptight and boring!
而这一位 发型很棒
But here, the hair is nicely coiffed,
妆容精致淡雅
the makeup is subtle and understated.
只可惜 衬衫太过紧绷 裙子也太紧了
However, the shirt is too sheer, and the skirt is too tight.
噢 噢 等等 我有话说
Uh-uh, hold up. Pause.
去年模拟招聘会
At job fair last year,
这套衣服夺冠了 我亲眼所见
this was the winnin' outfit. I seen it myself.
这也是为什么我挑这件
That's why I picked it instead
而不是那件超级惊艳的蓝裙子
of the blue dress I know I'd look bangin' in.
在此我们讲一下
Let's talk a moment about
搭配自身身材肤色的着装品味
dressing for your body type and your skin tone.
一位身材丰满的女人
A fuller-figured woman
应该挑选宽松一点的服装
might wanna choose a looser-fitting garment,
也许选择一件裙子而不是衬衫加半身裙
perhaps a dress as opposed to a shirt and a skirt.
但也不要那么宽松 比如一件肥大的夏威夷粗麻长袍
Not as loose as this, which resembles a large burlap muumuu.
-才不是呢
- No shit.
但是宝石色调搭配拼接色的围巾
But something in a jewel tone with a contrasting scarf.
-反正我看着自己挺美 -嘿 我看上去还是超专业的
- I know I look good. - Man, I still look hella office.
我一进门 他们就会被镇住 哇 她好专业哦
I walk in, they be like, "Yeah, she know her business".
没错
Yeah!
那么 谁赢了呢
So, who wins?
总体来说 撇去眼影过重
Overall, despite the excessive eye makeup,
我会选择站在那儿的年轻女士
I would have to give it to this young lady right here.
没错 就是这么拽 我们才是赢家
That's right, Latina, we the winna.
不敢相信 你居然给了连恰恰都跳得乱七八糟的人
Man, you gave it to Franken-cha-cha?
这真是胡说八道 眼光差到无可救药
This is some bullshit, shit to the bull.
该死的 那个库尔先约了你出去吃晚饭么
Damn, that Kool take you out to dinner first?
嘿 你听起来就像玛莎
Man, you sound just like Marsha.
你知道她就在厨房那儿
You know she right there in that kitchen.
我才不在乎 再过两天我就离开这个破地方了
Like I care. Only got two weeks left in this shit hole.
小姑娘 你就像一条龙
Little girl, you look like a
鼻孔出烟的龙
dragon with all that smoke coming out of your nose.
拜托 你抽烟的时候就像轰隆作响的排气管
Please, you smoke like a hooptie's tailpipe,
在街道上喷来喷去
puffin' up and down the street.
我是成年人 我有权利做任何选择 包括坏的
I'm an adult, it gives me the right to make bad choices.
我们正打算去瑞利家
We heading over to Rayleen's
吃点美味 一起去么
for something delicious. Care to join us?
我得工作
I gotta work.
当然 我们也工作 但是
Well, we working, too, except
我们的工作可不会让我们有油脂臭味儿
our work doesn't leave us smelling like rancid oil.
是啊 你干净得像毒贩子一样
Yeah, you clean as a drug-dealin' whistle.
你想要拒绝我 可以直接简单地说 不用谢谢
You should decline an offer by simply saying, "No, thank you."
否则 别人以后就不会邀请你了
Otherwise, people will stop inviting you to things.
我可以去吃
I could eat.
那就来吧 滋补一下你的身子
Well, come on, then, let's nourish that body.
拜拜 美味妞
Bye-bye, Taystee Girl.
哼哼
Mmm-hmm.
你确定不想出去吃点什么吗
Sure you not tryin' to come out and eat, though?
不 RJ 我有活得干
No, RJ, I gotta get to work.
好吧 自己小心
All right, be safe, though.
鸡肉味杯面有货了吗
Is the chicken flavor Cup of Noodles back in stock,
还是你们只剩下鲜虾味了
or have you only got the shrimp?
我们有奶油鸡肉味的
We got cream of chicken.
不 我不喜欢那个
No, I don't like that one.
那你要鲜虾味的
You want shrimpy?
好吧 给我五份
Sure, I'll take five of those,
还有金枪鱼不要配辣酱 只要原味的
and I don't want the tuna with the spicy sauce, just plain tuna.
哦 还有咖啡要浓的 拜托了
Oh, and for the coffee, the dark roast, please.
健身健得怎么样 O Neill
How's the fitness going, O'Neill?
4700下了 每天坚持10000多下
I'm in the forty-seven hundreds. Over 10,000 steps a day.
你会逐渐轻松的 现在还算早 锻炼得不错
You'll make it easy, it's still early, and good for you.
一步一步来嘛
One step at a time.
-呃欧 问题来了 -什么问题
- Uh-oh, problem. - What kind of problem?
账户没钱
No-money-in-account problem.
你说什么
What are you talking about?
给你家里打电话 我什么都没法卖给你
Call your family. I can't sell you shit.
抱歉 下一位
Sorry, next!
你知道我的植物都变什么样了吗
Do you understand what this is doing to my plants?
这上面都结霜了
There was frost on my succulent.
这可是沙漠植物 根本不应该结霜的
This is a desert plant, it should not be freezing.
听着 火炉得换一个了
Look, the furnace needs to be replaced.
我就算敲它一整天 都不可能热起来
I could dickpaw it all day. It's never getting hot again.
恩 就像你的老妈【一点都不火辣
Mmm, like your mother.
呵呵 一个 你妈 的玩笑 珍素有趣
Ah, delightful, a "Your mama" Joke? That's priceless.
菲格说了什么
What did Fig say?
你认为呢 她提了提她的裙子
What do you think? She hiked up her skirt...
然后呢
Yeah.
让我随便修一下旧炉子
told me to Band-Aid the old heap
然后就给了我50块去给她办公室买个暖气
and gave me 50 bucks to buy a space heater for her office.
所以你就像狗腿子一样帮她跑路
And you ran off like a good little puppy and you did it for her.
她才被算计了
Joke's on her.
暖气只要27块 我可纯赚了23块 伙计
Space heater cost 27 bucks, that's 23 bucks profit, man.
足够在时时乐吃两人晚餐了
That's dinner for two at Sizzler.
给你4块钱
Here's $4.
加上那个23块钱
Add it to the 23.
给我也买个那样的暖气 不然我就去告状
Buy me one of those space heaters, or I'm gonna rat you out.
你没法去时时乐吃饭了
No Sizzler for you.
艹
Shit.
别忘了 女士们 你们平常饮食中包含1500卡路里
Don't forget, ladies, your usual meal is 1,500 calories.
小心暴饮暴食
Beware of overeating.
嘿 你的小狗呢
Hey, where's your doggy?
额
Um...
看我有什么 看我有什么 这就对了 这就对了
Look what I got, look what I got. That's right, that's right.
哦 你喜欢这个 对么 没错 没错
Oh! You love that, don't you? Yeah, yeah.
你只要舔 舔 舔 你喜欢花生酱 不是么
You just lick, lick, lick. You like peanut butter, don't you?
你喜欢舔它 对吧 噢 舔一下 舔一下 舔一下
You like to lick that, don't you? Oh, just lick, lick, lick.
好好舔
Lick.
它变得很奇怪
It got weird.
那 好吧
Oh, okay.
看谁来了
Look who's here.
我该告诉格洛丽亚么
Should I tell Gloria?
不用了 几周前格洛丽亚说罗娅可以来吃
Nah, a few weeks ago, Gloria said the roja could eat,
只是她直到现在才来
but she just never came in till now.
为什么要放了她
Why'd she let her off the hook?
你想想 她已经失去厨房的管理权了
Well, you got to figure, she lost her kitchen,
又失去了姐妹 连头发都变得这么槽糕
she lost her girls, and her hair is all fucked up.
让她吃些劣质食品过活吧
Let her have some shitty food and get on with her life.
如果决定权在我
If it was up to me,
我就绝不会让她回来
I’d never let her back in here.
那可是头熊
That's a bear.
一只大俄国熊
A big Russian bear.
而现在
and right now...
她在隐忍直到再次变强壮
she's hibernating until she gets strong again
然后她就会后腿站立
And she’s gonna stand up on her back legs.
用她的熊掌和牙齿
and she's gonna shred up
撕碎所有人
everybody with her bear claws and her bear teeth.
你他妈怎么这么熟悉熊
What the fuck do you know about bears?
怎么 你住在布朗克斯动物园还是其他类似的地儿
What, you live by the Bronx Zoo or somethin'?
是红熊
Red bear.
你能在她眼中看出来
You can see it in her eyes.
胡说八道
You're full of shit.
才没 达亚才是胡说八道的人
No, Daya's the one who's full of shit.
是真的啦
It's true.
一点也不好笑 我整个人都不好了
It's not funny right now, I'm not in a good way.
她说的对 不开她玩笑是咱们的"屎"命
She's right, it's our "Doodie" Not to make fun of her.
是啊 因为那实在太"屎"啦
Yeah, 'cause that would be crappy.
你们两个菊花痒痒了么
You guys are such assholes.
起码这些菊花还在工作 噢 啪啦【指拉粑粑的声音
At least these assholes are working. Oh, snap!
犯人马丁尔斯 正在播报洗衣细节的任务
Inmate Martinez, report for an assignment at the laundry detail.
啊啊哦哦#￥%……&*
Ook-lay oo's-hay ere-hay.
讲人话 莫雷洛
Subtle, Morello.
我还是没法适应 你造吗
It's just still throwing me, you know?
看她没穿厨师外衣 那个心情你造吗
Not seeing her in her chef's jacket, you know?
嗯
Mmm.
就好比在厨房看到和你妹妹缠绵整晚的警官
It's like when you see a cop in sweat pants in your kitchen
正穿着长运动裤
after he's spent the night with your sister.
运动裤上还有精液 你感到特别不自在
Little splooge on the sweat pants, and you feel weird about it.
她说她看到了一坨狗屎
She said she's seeing some shit.
哦
Oh.
她正处于精神放空期
She's high as a kite on psych meds.
那可真糟糕
That's too bad.
要加入我们吗
Care to join us?
不了 谢谢
No, thanks.
在这很开心 安静和谐 但还是谢谢你
Happy here, nice and quiet, but thank you.
你随意就行
Suit yourself.
她来了
There she is.
佩恩
Penn.
嗨
Hi.
我们以为再也见不到你了 怎么样了
We didn't think we were ever gonna see you again, what happened?
我还记得的就是我曾经是天使
Last thing I remember is I was an angel.
呃 我听见你们互相殴打对方
Well, I heard y'all beat the holy mess out of each other.
是啊 我是说我记得她被揍得挺惨
Yeah, I mean, I suppose she got a few licks in.
呃 等会儿再和你说
Well, talk to you later.
我明白
I understand.
想要跳舞么
Would you like to dance?
嘿 费舍尔 最近怎么样
Hey, Fischer, how are you doing?
挺好的 先生 多谢关心 正在回归适应中
Fine, sir, thanks for asking, back in the swing of things.
那就好 道吉特 坐吧
Good to hear. Doggett, take a seat.
可以请你把门关上吗
Would you close the door, please?
出了禁闭了哈
So, out of the penalty box, huh?
不好意思 你说什么
I'm sorry, what?
没什么 知道曲棍球比赛的禁区么
Nothing. Penalty box. Hockey?
不不不 不是曲棍球比赛 希利先生 我之前在禁闭中
No, no, no. No hockey, Mr. Healy. I've been in SHU.
好像快一个多月了 对吧 一个月 是的
It's been like a month, I think, right? A month? Yeah.
所以他们放我出来 说我可以回来了
So they just pulled me out, said I was back.
我回来了吧
Am I back?
目前是的
For now.
我想你应该知道为什么叫你来这
I suppose you're wondering why I called you down here.
呃 劝告么 确保我不会再犯神经
Uh, counseling? Make sure I don't go cuckoo again?
我不会啦 我把所有魂魄都拿回来了
I won't. I got all my marbles back.
我想我们应该谈谈
I thought we should talk.
开诚布公地谈谈
Get things straight.
好吧
All right.
我想我能向你保证
I mean, I can promise you
我此刻再正常不过啦
that I've never felt more saner than I do now.
你懂的 当你在与世隔绝的地方度过漫漫长日
You know, when you spend that much time down there in solitude,
就像得到洗涤 你懂的 我的心灵感到很正常
it's like real purification. You know, my heart feels right.
我想你有时间去反省那个晚上
I suppose you had time to reflect on that evening, then?
不 我现在头昏脑涨
Nope, because my head is so fuzzy.
噢 真的是这样么
Oh? Is that so?
我的意思是 我遭受了各种撞击
I mean, I suffered multiple contusions and...
和挫伤 反复地疼痛
lacerations, and it's just freakin' painful,
由于经历过它
and now that I got through it,
我开始想起一些事 回忆起大量内容
I started to remember, and then lots of stuff came back to me.
对
Yep.
她冲你发火 你和她对峙 然后你们打起来了
She angered you, you confronted her, and you fought.
是的
Yes.
那就是故事的结局
That's it, end of story.
不 还没完
No, there's more.
还有什么
What more?
你们讨论了什么
What are you talking about?
讨论了比如安格鲁人啊
There's, like, angles, and there's,
比如减刑啊 还有
like, extenuations and then there's...
我不知道我看见了什么 道吉特
I didn't know what I was seeing, Doggett.
你听到我在说什么吗
Do you hear what I'm saying?
我想不明白你们两个会
I had no idea that you two were gonna...
你们原本可以好好谈谈的
You could have been having a talk,
甚至像恋人间的争吵  我不清楚
a lovers' quarrel, even, I don't know,
我的确没有看见武器
and I certainly didn't see a weapon.
节假日 精神压力增加
Holiday times, tensions get high.
我是说 谁会知道凯迪亚比先前更加暴怒
I mean, God knows Katya was testier than ever then,
但是想都别想
but don't think for a second
有人会信一个嗑药过度的乡巴佬而不信我
that anyone is gonna believe a meth-addled hillbilly over me.
最好百分之百搞清楚那点
Be 100% fucking clear about that.
呃 也许他们只是
Well, they might just...
相信海报女孩在做倡导生命权的运动
believe the poster girl for the right-to-life movement.
你知道吗 我曾经上过格莱塔·范·苏斯泰瑞的节目
You know, I was on Greta Van Susteren,
如果他们知道你想杀死我会怎么样
and what if they knew you were about to let me get killed?
我应该把你丢回去隔离起来 让你慢慢腐烂
I ought to throw you back in seg and let you rot.
要怎样才能让你忘记你捏造的事实
What would help you forget what you think you saw?
嗯
Mmm.
呃 我仍旧不确定
Uh, I'm still not sure how that
那怎么能解释预算的问题
answers the questions I have regarding the budget.
所以我今天才邀请你来啊
That's why I invited you today.
像《迈向成功的装束》《我们的招聘会》
Programs like Dress for Success, our job fair,
《我们的圣诞巡游》 《致读者》之类的节目
our Christmas pageant, Readers to Readers,
都不是通信部的首选
are not a top priority for the DOC,
但是对民心 教育 各方面康复而言
but they are so important for morale,
他们又是如此重要
for education, for rehabilitation.
除非我们能让政府进行大刀阔斧地改革
Until we can get the government on board for some serious reform,
资金的调整是必要的
a little shifting of funds is a necessity,
我保证所有的钱都会用于
but I assure you all of the money is being used
提高监狱犯人的生活
for the good of the prison and its residents.
好吧
Okay.
我发现你的丈夫正在参与州参议院
And I noticed that your husband is running for state senate.
他和你对教育一样热爱吗
Is your passion for education a value he shares?
当然
Absolutely.
嗯 不过如果你有任何问题想问詹森
Uh, but any questions you have for Jason,
可以直接去他办公室
you can direct towards his office.
希望我已经解释了一些关于钱
I hope I've shed some light on how the money
在利奇菲尔德是如何被用于让女囚受益的
is being used to benefit the inmates here at Litchfield.
呃 好吧 我还有一些问题
Uh, well, actually, I've got a few more questions...
真抱歉 恐怕我不得不赶紧投入工作中
Because I'm afraid, sadly, I have to get back to work.
监狱需要有人经营
Prison doesn't run itself.
我的意思是 她给了我件大号衣服 真是不合身
I mean, she gave me the freakin' outfit. It was one big setup.
所以现在两个黑人女孩 一个同性恋吸毒女孩
So now the two black girls, the lesbo junkie girl,
还有一些墨西哥人要开始做面试了
and some Mexican get to go on and do the interview part,
我却回来这里
and I'm back here.
呃 你的妆容看上去很漂亮
Well, your makeup looks real pretty.
比方说 我今天才发现你有睫毛
Like, I didn't even know you had eyelashes till today.
你看上去真的很漂亮
You look really nice.
谢了 安吉 你这么说真安慰
Thanks, Ange. That's nice of you to say.
嘿 你知道佩恩从禁闭中出来了
Hey, did you know that Penn's out of seg?
- 什么 - 嗯哼
- What? - Mmm-hmm.
你怎么知道的
How do you know?
因为吃过午饭 走过希利办公室的时候 我看到她了
'Cause I seen her, after lunch, walking to Healy's office.
她看上去怎么样
How'd she look?
她看上去很衰
She looked pretty rough.
我是 和现在相比 以前她的牙都不算糟
I mean, if her teeth was bad before?
哇哦 真是没剩几颗牙了
Woof, ain't much left in there.
警卫汤普森去塔楼
Guard Thompson to the tower.
我这样说是不是很不好 但是自从她离开
Don't get me wrong or nothin, ' but since she's been away,
这儿 好像 这里变得好起来了
hasn't it been, like, kind of nice in here?
- 你的意思是 - 我不清楚 就像
- What do you mean? - I don't know, like...
更平静舒适了
like, peaceful, easy.
没有大呼小叫 没人说大家都要下地狱了
No yelling, no telling everyone they're going to hell, just...
就是很安宁 你懂么
Just quiet, you know?
懂啊
Yeah.
不过你不会告诉她我说话 对吧
But you won't tell her I said nothing, right?
当然不会
'Course not.
女士们 检查洗衣间的工作任务
Ladies, check the board for work assignments.
帕波现在在哪儿
So, where's Piper now?
仍旧在芝加哥 我猜的
Still in Chicago, I imagine it.
拉里 我想谈谈你 不是她
Larry, I wanted to talk about you, not her.
她呆在那儿 芝加哥
She staying there? In Chicago?
她讨厌深盘披萨
She hates deep-dish.
不知道她是不是继续待在那里
Don't know if she's staying.
别以为她在那儿能吃得上披萨
Don't think she's eating a whole lot of pizza.
- 拉里 - 你怎么看她
- Larry... - How'd she seem to you?
要我看 她就是个大煞笔
Seemed like an idiot to me.
我给过她建议 但是她不听
I gave her advice, and she didn't take it.
你爱过她 但是她背叛了你
You gave her love, and she cheated on you.
我又不是粉丝 别说这话题了
I'm not a fan, and end of topic.
- 我想她 - 儿子 那就找点事分散注意力吧
- I miss her. - Well, then, find a distraction, son,
不会让你忧郁 成天吃垃圾食品
something that doesn't involve moping around, eating crap
- 玩玩魔兽世界啦 - 魔兽争霸
- and playing that World of Warlock. - Warcraft.
魔兽争霸 好极了
Warcraft, perfect.
你也可以加入坦克军团 另一种消遣
You can join the tank corps, another waste of time.
去和人上床嘿咻
Go get laid.
- 我还没准备好 - 准备什么
- I'm not ready. - For what?
准备把你的鸡鸡深入
For sticking your dick in
可爱的新鲜地儿 然后四出抽动么
something new and cute and moving it around?
所有男人都准备好这个了
All guys are ready for that.
那边的两人随时待命
These two over here are ready for it any moment now.
继续你的生活
Get on with your life.
你是对的 不 你真的是对的
You're right. No, you're right.
她背叛我了 对吧 我是说
She cheated, right? I mean...
她说谎了 为什么我还要耿耿于怀
She lied, why am I holding on?
监狱改变了她 它能改变人
Prison changed her. It changes people.
- 我听过那个 - 我是说 她再也不是同性恋了
- I heard that. - I mean, she was not a lesbian anymore,
不再和我一起了
not with me.
你知道 然后她进监狱啦
You know? Then she's in prison,
才多久 几个星期 骗鬼吧 然后又变成同性恋
what, a few weeks? Bam! A lesbian again.
或者双性恋 我甚至都不知道
Or bi? I don't even know.
对我们两个都好 我知道的
It was good with us, I know it was.
我觉得 混蛋 我是说 如果那也是谎言的话怎么办
I think, shit, I mean, what if that was a lie, too?
但我不觉得是 我不觉得
But I don't think it was, I don't think it was, I mean,
你懂的 我知道我有一些天赋
you know, I know I have some talent,
我很细心周密
I'm very attentive and thorough,
你懂的 我工作做得很好 我不是个小人物
you know, I do good work, I'm not small.
- 拉里 - 你说得对 我应该走出去
- Larry. - You're right, I should get out there.
我需要挣脱出困境 我要走出去
I need to get out there. I'm gonna get out there.
我让她阴道高潮了 你知道有多难么
I made her come vaginally, do you know how hard that is to do?
- 拜托 拉里 - 我说的重点是
- Please, Larry. - My point is...
我甚至都不知道我的重点是什么
I don't even know what my point is anymore.
- 爸爸 - 啊
- Dad? - Yeah?
我们为什么会来同志专用澡堂
Why did you bring us to a gay bathhouse?
这里不错啊又干净 基佬是有他们的优点的
It's a nice place, clean. A shvitz is a shvitz.
-我只是有这里的团购券而已 -啊 我懂了
- I had a Groupon. - Ah, gotcha.
诶 等一下 就是说我可以写在我简历上咯
Wait, so, I could put that on my résumé thing?
-帮我表哥干活  -可以
- Workin' for my cousin? - Sure.
不过措辞要改一下
But instead of saying that
你不要说 防止有人来偷东西啥的
you helped make sure that no one stole shit,
你可以说你管理库存 负责安保嘛
you could say that you monitored inventory and provided security.
啊 好滴好滴 我懂了 可以哟
Ah, okay, okay, I see that, I could do that.
我想要做一份可以让我放松的工作 懂不
I want the kind of job where I could just chill, you know?
轻轻松松 核对检查啥的
Chill out, collect a check.
这份个人倾向测试说呢
According to this aptitude test,
我应该成为一名职业运动员
I should be a professional athlete,
公园巡警 或者是惩教人员
a park ranger, or a correctional officer.
在Storky食品中心干过活
Working at Storky's means I
说明我在食品服务领域有经验
have experience in the food service industry.
对啦
That's it.
因为我记性好 算数快
And because I can remember shit and add real fast,
说明我有良好的记忆力以及超常的算数能力
I have high retention abilities and exceptional math skills.
上路子了啊
You're getting it.
我想嫁给克里斯多夫 跟他生孩子
Well, I just wanna get married to Christopher and have his babies
把房子打扮的漂漂亮亮的
and make the house look nice.
或许在阳光下 像是在沙滩
Maybe in the sunshine, like on the beach,
周围都是 嗯  美人儿们
surrounded by, mmm, beautiful people.
你造吗 你刚刚跟一个犯人说
Are you at all aware that you just told an inmate in prison
她应该去当狱警诶
that she should become a correctional officer?
你丫没毛病吧
What the fuck is wrong with you?
我的确想当职业运动员
I do want to be a professional athlete,
可是不是你说做就能做的
but you just don't snap your fingers and become that.
我以前想要去帮有心理问题的小孩儿
I was hoping to work with mentally ill children.
我觉得我能够为他们以后的生活
I think I could offer some
提供一些见解啥的
insight into what they might be experiencing
让他们治愈 康复
and help them to heal and recover.
也许我可以上品趣网 听说貌似有这个东西
Maybe I'll Pinterest. I hear that's a thing.
我从一个穿着修女服人变成了穿囚服的
I went from wearing a habit to wearing a prison uniform.
我觉得时装界
I don't think the fashion
也许对我而言不是个合适的的选择
industry would be a viable option for me.
我还喜欢工作时有圆圆的东西
I would also like to work with round objects.
耶 圆圆的东西我超级喜欢的
Yeah, round things are very pleasing to me.
或许我可以为女排当裁判
Maybe I can umpire women's softball.
这样我就可以被上了
Then I could get laid.
而且哪 我押韵也押的很好 这个要咋说来着
So I also can rhyme real good. What do I say about that?
热爱诗歌
Poetic inclinations.
哈
Ha!
对头 我就是想说这个来着
That's what I'm talking about!
看着没 我跟你 咱俩能成好伙伴
See, you and me, we gonna be friends!
耶 来击掌 击掌 来嘛
Yeah, give it to me! Give it to me!
耶 这就是我想说的
Yeah! That's what I'm talking about.
好 继续
Now let's keep going.
瓦西里 你的脸怎么了
Vasily, what happened to your face?
甘尼亚那帮人打你了
Did Ganya's people do that to you?
不 没有 妈 琳达拿一包硬币砸了我的脸
No. No, Ma. Lida hit me in the face with a bag of change.
什么
What?
她桌子上有一包
She has this bag of
洗衣服用的硬币
quarters for the laundry sitting on the table.
我晚上回来 喝的有点醉 她随手拿起来就砸
I stumbled in late a little drunk. She grabbed it, and whack.
她可真有种
Good for her.
啊 老妈 你可真有同情心 多谢
Yeah, I appreciate your sympathy, Ma, thank you.
我把你养大并不是让你醉醺醺的回家让你老婆担心
I didn't raise you to come home drunk and upset your wife.
她不是我老婆
She's not my wife.
她是我孙子的妈妈 你说我该叫她什么
She's the mother of my grandson, what should I call her?
一个伤害你宝贝儿子的暴力狂
A violent criminal who hurt your baby boy.
-这儿疼死了  -你为什么不跟她结婚
- This hurts, Ma. - Why won't you marry her?
她是个好姑娘 她能镇得住你
She's a nice girl, she puts up with you.
我害怕承诺
I have a fear of commitment.
好吧 妈 为什么不聊聊你的生活
Okay, mamochka, why don't we talk about you for a little bit?
因为我的生活悲哀渺小 对我爱的人而言是个负担
Because my life is sad and small and a burden to those I love.
你老爸这个月都没给我打生活费
Papa didn't put any money in the account this month.
-发生什么了 -你想知道发生什么了吗
- What's going on? - Wanna know what's going on?
老妈 商店空了 好嘛
Ma, the store is empty, okay?
大家都不敢进去
Everyone's afraid to go in
因为他们知道 甘尼亚在生你和爸的气
because they know Ganya's mad at you and Pop
因为你们无视监狱的合同
for blowing the prison contract.
我一进来就给他合同了
I got him that contract in the first place.
是吗 或许你应该提醒他
Yeah? Well, maybe you should remind him,
也许他不记得了呢
because he doesn't remember that part.
你爸为什么不来呢
Why didn't Papa come?
他整天待在商店里 一直到半夜
He's at the store all day, half the night,
他就坐在那儿 等人来
he just sits there, waiting for someone to come in.
没人帮他 妈
He's got no help, Ma.
-那 你为什么不帮他呢
- So, why don't you help him?
-我要工作 我也有家庭
- Ma, I'm working. I got a family, too.
难道我不想去他那儿 多帮帮他吗
Don't you think I wish I can go there and help him out some more?
或许你说的对 我应该去上大学的
You know, maybe I should've gone to college like you said.
-那尤里和马克西姆呢
- What about Yuri and Maxim?
-我们都在干活 我们很忙
- We're all working. We're all hustling.
我们都要当心拥有武器的疯女人  知道吗
We're all trying to avoid crazy women with weapons, okay?
现在是艰苦时期
It's just rough times right now.
我要振作起来
I'm gonna put some things together.
我下周给你钱 我保证
I'll get you money next week, I promise.
谢谢
Thank you.
你是个好儿子 虽然不是多棒 不过还算好
You're a good son. Not great, but pretty good.
我当是表扬了
I'll take it.
上帝 她长变了啊
God, she already looks so different.
-是啊 -你好啊
- Yeah. - Hello!
是滴 没错 我是你麻麻
Yeah, that's right, I'm your mommy!
我太太太爱你了 你造吗
And I love you so, so, so much!
很快呢
And soon we're gonna be
我们就要在一起啦 我保证
spending lots of time together, I promise.
在你记事前 我们就会在一起了
Before you can even remember stuff, we're gonna be together.
是什么时候来着 一般几岁开始记事的
When is that? When you can remember?
大概 四 五岁那会 对吧
Like, when you're four or five, right?
好像我四岁就能记事了呢
I think I remember something from when I was four.
不知道
Don't know.
哦
Oh!
她的头闻起来好棒
Her head smells so good.
她长得像你 不过很漂亮
And she looks like you, you know, but pretty.
嗯嗯
Mmm-hmm.
她是不是个好宝宝
Is she a good baby?
-她睡的好不好 吃的怎么样 -嗯
- Does she sleep okay? Is she eating? - Yeah.
-跟你聊天真好 -嗯
- It's so good talking to you. - Yeah.
瞧啊 我一点也不担心 面试绝必不成问题
See, I ain't worried. I'm gonna rock that interview,
之后 我就会成为招聘会上的王者啦
then I'm gonna be the winner of the job fair
接下来我会得到一份真正的工作
and they gonna hook me up with a real job.
比如给那些名人当个助理什么的
I'm gonna be like an assistant
比如说乔布朗 或者其他电视评委
to Judge Joe Brown or one of them TV judges.
甚至还可能是茱迪
Or maybe even Judy.
是啊 她根本不听任何人的 好嘛
Yeah, man, she don't take shit from nobody!
我觉得我们肯定合得来
I know we'd vibe.
哟 你特么的在聊啥呢 工作哈
Yo, what the fuck are you talkin' about, real job?
去年 一个女生表现的最好
Last year, the girl who did the best,
她刚一获释
the job fair people hooked
就在招聘会上找到了一份工作
her up with a real job once she was released.
他们没有跟大家宣布 因为大家听了肯定要疯掉
They don't announce it or nothing 'cause people get all crazy,
不过她小声告诉我的
but she told me on the low-low.
-等等 去年是谁赢了 -波科诺
- Wait, who won last year? - Pocano.
-奥坎波 -长着痦子的菲律宾小妞么
- Ocampo? - The Filipino chick with the mole?
奥坎波
Ocampo.
就是那个在木工店干过活的人
Man, the one that worked in the woodshop.
她获得最佳着装奖 还有最佳简历
She won for best outfit, and she had the best résumé.
你怎么不告诉我还有奖呢
Why didn't you tell us there was a prize?
你想啥呢 我们是竞争对象好嘛
Man, why you think? We are the competition.
现在我们出局了 所以
Now we out the way, so
只剩下她还有那个又矮又瘦的墨西哥人
it's just her and the little skinny Mexican
明天去参加面试
doing the interview tomorrow.
姐们儿 这可不对了 你早该告诉我们的
Man, that shit ain't right, man, you should've told us.
但是我是体系里的人
But I'm a child of the system,
没有人教我区分是非
no one ever taught me right from wrong.
草泥马
Girl, fuck you!
就你穿着那个大袍子还想赢过我
Like you would've did better in your potato sack?
我获得了机会 我这么做是为了大家
Man, I got a chance here, and I'm doing it for all of us.
喂 拜托 我需要你们给我投票
Man, come on! I need y'all rootin' for me.
别让那个小豆芽赢了
We can't let Skinny Bean win.
她们已经占了厨房
They already got the kitchen,
还有电影院最佳坐席
and they got the best seats at movie night.
-这倒是 -是啊
- True. - True.
这次也想让给她们吗
Y'all gonna let them take this, too?
我给过你机会 我给过你无数次机会
You had your shot. You had several shots.
现在你想要改变心意了吗 滚粗
Now you got a change of heart? Get outta here.
我在那儿待不下去了
I can't stay no more in that place,
换一家也还是待不下去
and I can't start over in another home.
打扰一下 女士
Excuse me, ma'am?
我刚刚路过你的铺子
I was just walking through your store,
我想买点泡沫包装纸
hoping to buy some bubble wrap
然后给我卡罗莱纳州的阿姨再寄点巧克力
and maybe ship some chocolates to my aunt in Carolina.
我只能给你泡沫包装纸
And that's about all I'm gonna sell you, is some bubble wrap,
巧克力什么的哈 不好意思 出门右拐
anything else, you've got the wrong shop.
你说啥呢 咱俩挺好啊 我上月还给你800块呢
What you talking about? We all good. I paid you $800 last month.
是嘛 你想让我去查账吗
For real? You gonna make me go to the books?
他给过你800块了 对不
He paid you $800, right?
那按照销量算
What was the initial
最初达成协议的价格是多少
agreed-upon price for the quantity in question?
哎哟哟 瞧瞧你 说大话唬人啊
Well, look at you, using your big words.
一千两百五 之前他还欠我130块
$1,250. Plus, he owes me $130 from before.
1250块 130块 那他总共欠你580块
$1,250 and $130. He in the hole to you for $580,
除非还有利息
unless there's a vig.
你个笨蛋 当然有利息了
You can bet your ass there's a vig.
那就是182块钱
So that would bring it up to $182,
加上分批付款的50块罚金的话
plus $50 penalty for partial payment on the $1,250,
一共是682块
now we talkin' $682.
算的可真精啊
Fuckin' Goldberg over here.
拜托啊 微 我还有几个客户等我呢
Come on, Vee, I got customers waitin' on me.
你是我的批发商 就帮帮我嘛
You're my wholesaler. Help a brother out.
你怎么看
What you think?
他看起来相当滴绝望
I think he seem pretty desperate.
那就给他一半好了
I say give him half now and
等还了债在给他另一半
the other half when that debt drops to zero.
真特么操蛋
This is fucked.
你给我小心点
Careful, now.
现在他签了1307块
He up to $1,307 now.
周末过来找我
You find me by week's end.
哎呦 看起来在垃圾食品店里
Well, looks like adding up all them little nickels and dimes
学了两下子
at Burger McFat-Ass done
还挺会算数的嘛 美味妞
taught you a thing or two, huh, Taystee Girl?
准备好开工了么
You ready to work?
我去检查一下库存
I'm gonna go check on inventory.
-嘿 -多谢上帝 进来
- Hey. - Oh, thank God. Come in.
-你带啤酒了吗 -科罗娜啤酒 对吧
- Did you bring the beer? - Coronas, right?
不 不 不 是黑啤
No! No, no, no, dark beer.
我叫你买黑啤的嘛 这样我才能出奶
It's supposed to be dark beer. It helps my milk come in.
我他妈的又不是做鱼饼
I'm not making fucking fish tacos,
拉里 我在喂奶
Larry. I'm trying to feed my child.
你把黑啤带来了 谢谢
And you brought the dark beer, thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
抱歉 我最近脾气太差
I'm sorry, I'm going bat-shit.
额 波莉 你的胸部 有点
Uh, Polly, your breast is kind of...
哦 经常会露出来 我们家成了快递小哥最喜欢的地方
Please, they're always out. I'm the UPS guy's new favorite stop.
嘿 你最近有没有跟帕波聊过
Hey, have you talked to Piper at all?
没有 你知道的
No, and you know that.
我知道你们分手了
And I know you broke up.
我知道她都要疯了
And I know she freaked out
还被送去住在鞋子里还是什么的
and got sent to live in a shoe or something,
现在她又在芝加哥 她超级讨厌芝加哥厚底披萨
and now she's in Chicago. She fucking hates deep-dish.
我也知道
I know!
这些我都是从她妈妈那听来的
Well, I heard all this from her mom.
听着 拉里 她是我的朋友
Look, Larry, she's my friend,
跟你比我永远都会站在她那边
and I'll always take her side over yours,
而我会永远都是她的朋友
and I'll always be friends with her,
谁知道我又能和你相处多久呢
and who knows how long I'll know you?
但是就事论事的话 我觉得她就是个
But just between us, I think she's
白痴 自甘堕落加犯傻
being an idiot and self-destructive and stupid,
在这一点上我一直都同情你
and my sympathies are with you all the way on this one.
好吧 谢谢你
Well, thank you.
谢什么 我什么都没说过
For what? I never said a thing.
我从不和你谈论帕波
I don't talk about Piper with you.
那样是对她背叛也是错的
That would be disloyal and wrong.
明白了
Gotcha.
那么 皮特什么时候回来
So, when is Pete back?
我不知道 也许我不会允许他回来
I don't know, I may not let him come back.
孩子还不到三个月大
The baby is less than three months old
然后突然他就得
and suddenly he has to
去什么狗屁冻原做野外探索
go on a vision quest in the fucking tundra?
为了公平来讲 他说是你让他去的
Well, to be fair, he said you told him to go.
我是个激素混乱的笨蛋 我不是真心的
I'm a hormonal moron! I didn't mean it.
我没想到他真的走了
I didn't think he would actually go.
我已经三天没洗澡了 拉里
I haven't showered in three days, Larry.
我妈一整个星期都在参加什么该死的纸牌联赛
My mother is in a fucking pinochle tournament for the whole week,
而不是待在旁边帮忙
not that she's any help when she's here,
我还没有一个杀千刀的婴儿护理
and I don't have a goddamn baby
因为我正努力适应养育孩子
nurse because I'm trying attachment parenting,
真是狗屎一样
and it's fucking bullshit.
过来 在他被我的眼泪和臭汗淹死前帮我抱住他
Here, take this child before I drown him in my tears and sweat.
嘿 嘿嘿 小伙子 你好啊
Hey, hey, hey, buddy, hello.
你好 宝贝 嗨 我是你拉里叔叔
Hello, baby, hi, it's your Uncle Larry.
嗨 你好吗 小朋友
Hi, how's it going, buddy?
我们今天晚上要一起玩耍了 伙计 耶
We're gonna hang out tonight, man, yeah.
我们晚上订些泰国菜
We're gonna order some Thai food,
也许看会儿电视 觉得怎么样啊
maybe watch a little TV. How's that sound?
这样满意吗
Cool with that?
我要洗个澡 你能给他换尿片吗
I'm gonna take a shower. Can you change him?
行啊 我的意思是 好 我试一下
Yeah, I mean, sure, I can try.
好
Okay.
嗯
Mmm!
他还行啊 看起来挺开心的
He's all new and just happy.
是啊 别着急 我和皮特会把这些毁的一干二净
Yep, don't worry, Pete and I will fuck that right up.
不 这是真的吗
No, is that true?
来 这不是真的 你会一直都很开心的 小伙子 是不
Come, now. That's not true. You stay happy, buddy, okay?
你只要 你只需要一直保持开心 好吗
You just... you just stay happy, all right?
你知道吗 在你还是个婴儿的时候我就这样想了
You know, I got the idea from when you was a baby.
谁也不许给你酸奶喝
No one was allowed to ever give you yogurt,
因为你他妈的会像爆炸一样
'cause you would, like, fucking explode.
弄得到处都是屎
There'd be shit everywhere.
你后背上 头发里 真是太恶心了
Up your back, in your hair. It was so disgusting.
但是现在你这本事派得上用场了 是吧
But now it's coming in handy, right?
是吗
Right?
有效吗
Is it working?
拜托你能不能给我点隐私啊
Could you just please give me some privacy here?
你真的让我感觉非常非常的不舒服
You're making me really, really uncomfortable.
我是你妈
I'm your mother.
天啊 你还能不能让我愉快的拉屎了
God, can I just shit in peace?
好吧
Fine.
但是如果你有动静了 一定要告诉我 好吗
But if you have any action, you let me know, okay?
-我是真心的关心你 -好吧 好吧 走开行吗
- I fucking care. - Fine, fine, just go.
好吧 过来 站起来
All right, here, stand up.
现在腰那个地方应该更合适了
This should fit you better around the waist now.
是啊 谢谢你 皮
Yeah, thanks for lookin' out, P.
为家人就该这么做
It's what you do for family.
是啊 怎么了 你现在是我的疯阿姨普斯了
Yeah, what, you my crazy Aunt Poussey now?
不是 我是你的异姓姐姐
No, I'm your sister from another mister
你要是不把那本书看的滚瓜烂熟
about to beat your ass down if
我就把你揍得屁股开花
you don't read that book till you know it cold.
你要参加欢脱的面试呢
You got some interview ass-kickin' to do.
让我为你骄傲吧
Make me proud.
猜猜谁回来了还空前的嗨 嘿
Guess who's back and better than ever? Hey!
我知道你说的是找些图标
I know you said to get AnyStamp,
但是那个收藏小店简直太有趣了
but the hobby shop was mad fun, yo!
你去过那吗
You ever been in there?
让我想买下所有手工 还有粉彩
Made me wanna get all crafty, get some puffy paint,
或者是一台莱茵石机
or a rhinestone machine.
他们有一整过道都是管道清理器
They had a whole fucking aisle of pipe cleaners!
管道清理器
Pipe cleaners!
伙计 在我们这窝里 我们就只有
Man, in group home, all we
破烂的彩笔和干了的粘合棍子
got was broken crayons and dried up glue sticks.
我们这是要包装海洛因呢还是要装饰杂志呢
Are we marking scag-bags or we decorating your journal?
我也搞不懂了 微
I don't know, though, Vee.
我的意思是 也许你想
I mean, maybe you wanna
考虑一下挑一个做商标呢 你说呢
consider one of these for your trademark, you know?
粘几个到包装袋上
Glue a pair of these on every bag,
或者叫它唯我独尊 你说呢
or call it googly smag, you know?
其他团伙都去死吧
Shit's all gangster!
好吧 也许我是有点着迷了
All right, maybe I got a little carried away,
但是看这些东西多可爱啊
but look how cute this one is.
可以把零钱找给我吗
Can I have my change, please?
我可不是派你带着百元大钞去
I did not send you to the
商店然后带着星星眼回来的
store with a C-note to bring back googly eyes.
好吧
Okay.
但是说正经的
But for serious,
像是 为什么你不用个其他的什么做图标呢
like, why couldn't you use something different for a stamp?
像是这个猫头鹰先生
Like Mr. Owl here?
人们就稀罕这玩意 不是吗
People do this shit, right?
就像 包装上都有各种酷毙了的玩意
Like, there's dope with all sorts of crazy shit on it.
这无关于你在包装上放什么
It's not about what you put on the package,
这与你产品的质量有关
it's about the quality of your product.
我不知道 话虽这样说 但她还是有几分对的
I don't know, though, she kind of right.
你选一些奇怪的东西
You pick something weird,
人们一定会有印象的
people gonna remember that shit for sure.
那个猫头鹰看起来像醉了
That owl looks drunk.
我喜欢那个马和那辆脚踏车
I like the horse and the bicycle.
好吧 比方说我们用这个马
Okay, say we use the horse.
叫我们的货为像马的马 懂吗
Call our shit Horsey Horse, get it?
因为海洛因就被称为马 耶 这可是钱啊
Because heroin's called horse. Yo, that's money!
我告诉你 人们会喜欢的 哇哦
I'm telling you, people be like, "Ooh,
我需要更多的 像马的马
"I need me some more of that Horsey Horse.
这货真是不错
This shit was so good!"
不知不觉 你就有了自主品牌啦
Before you know it, you've got a call brand.
听听 她想要教我怎么做事
Listen to her trying to teach me how to deal.
你们都嘲笑我 但是我告诉你
Y'all laughing now, but I'm telling you,
有一天当我在华尔街时 你们可以前来拜访我
come visit me one day when I'm on Wall Street
并且让某个白人男孩给我置备午餐
and having some white boy get me lunch,
我正处理一宗以前的大单 然后他告诉我
and I'm wheelin' a big old deal, and he talking about,
杰弗逊夫人 2号线有您电话
"Ms. Jefferson, you have a call on line two."
我觉得你看电影看多了
Think you've been watching too many movies.
我只是想说 嘿 我可不想一辈子都干这份工作
I'm just saying, yo, this is not my forever career.
小姑娘 你生长在这片破地方
Girl, you from this hood,
你没有事业生涯 你只有一份工作
you don't get a career, you get a job.
这里可是周围薪水最好的地方了
This right here is the best-paying job around.
尽管说教吧
Preach it, Vee.
-你造人们最尊敬啥 金钱 -恩
- You know what people respect? Money. - Hmm.
你不断为我工作 你就能得到钱
You keep working for me, that's exactly what you gonna have.
我说的对么 RJ 难道我会不关心我的人
Ain't that right, RJ? Don't I take care of my people?
-没错 夫人 -呃 随便啦
- Yes, ma'am. - Eh, whatever.
看这 尝尝着 靓女 告诉我要不要再加点盐了
Look here, taste this, girl. Tell me if it needs some more salt.
-恩 好吃 -我就知道
- Mmm! That is good. - I know.
-这是啥 南瓜吗 -白胡桃泥和姜
- What's that, pumpkin? - Butternut squash and ginger,
-然后我又加了点韭葱 -嗯
- and I threw in some leeks, just 'cause. - Mmm!
好 现在 RJ听着
All right, now, listen, RJ,
把桌子清理掉 把沙拉拿到桌上去
clear off that table, grab this salad.
还有谁回家吃饭吗
- Is anybody else coming home for dinner?
额 就我们吧
- Uh, think it's just us.
好吧 请拿些碗
All right, grab some bowls, please.
噢 不错 噢 美味极了
Oh, yes, ooh, this smells good.
去拿些碗垫 好吗
Get the placemats. All right.
像马的马
"Horsey Horse".
有点意思 但是
That's kind of fun. But, Lord,
上天是仁慈的 这很愚昧 就和你一样
have mercy, it's silly, just like you.
我今晚为你们尝试做了一种全新的面包
I tried a new bread tonight, y'all.
一种带有亚麻籽的全麦面包
It's a whole grain flaxseed bread.
你们吃饭时都要多吃一些纤维食物
Y'all need some more fiber in your diet.
也去拿把刀来切面包 尝尝看
Grab a knife for this bread, too, Taste.
把碗拿来 靓女 你还在等啥
Bring the bowls, girl. What you waiting for?
嗨 红妈
Hey, Red.
这些位子绝佳啊 从这边可以好好的欣赏舞台
These are great seats, you can really see the stage from here.
你们不必如此
You really don't need to do this.
我是说 我很感谢你们的示好以及一切 但是
I mean, I appreciate the gesture and everything, but...
但是啥 我们会被排除吗 早就没人注意我们了
But what? We'll be ostracized? Already no one notices us.
我们又老又瞎 所以我们为啥不结伴呢
We're old and invisible, so why not be old together?
我们相互也能有个照应
We keep each other company.
你说我老
You calling me old?
我才23岁
I'm 23.
变得成熟感觉如何 就像一颗枝繁叶茂的大树
How about matured? Like a big, branchy tree.
带有雪白的根部
With snow-white roots.
-哦 该死的 看来我得应付这一切了 是吗
- Oh, shit. I gotta deal with that, huh? -
或者就不管它 他妈的
Or just let it go. Fuck it.
我们想要打动的是谁啊
Who we trying to impress?
在她23岁时 看起来有些粗糙了
She looks rough for 23.
我们去哪
Where we going?
去镇上
We're going to town.
真的吗
Really?
医疗中心 她要去看口腔外科
Medical center. She's going to the oral surgeon.
希望你有很多很多那样的杂志
Hope you got lots of those magazines,
因为这段时间太漫长了
'cause it's gonna be hours and hours and hours.
哦 我多着呢
Oh, I got plenty.
而且我还能听听广播 我没事的
And I got my radio shows. I'll be fine.
祝你好运 道吉特
Good for you, Doggett.
-祝贺祝贺 -谢谢
- Congratu-fucking-lations. - Thank you.
没错
That's right,
我们菲利普莫里斯公司坚信有重新改过的机会
we at the Philip Morris Companies believe in second chances.
我们欢迎那些能够在一个高度有序规范的坏境中
We welcome people who can handle the challenges
能够处理在专门为成人生产和销售的产品中
of manufacturing and marketing products meant for adults
所带来的挑战
in a highly regulated and restricted environment
与此同时 每天都力求履行自己的职责 谢谢
while striving each day to operate responsibly. Thank you.
伙计 我以为特别来宾意味着像莫妮克
Man, I thought special guests meant like Mo'Nique
或者韦斯利斯奈普斯或者其他人
or Wesley Snipes or somethin.'
而不是某些他妈的卖雪茄的狂热分子来提醒我们
Not some cigarette-hawkin' fuck-nut reminding us
唯一的一个想雇佣重罪犯的人
that the only people who want to hire felons
已经被所有人都唾弃了
are already hated by everybody else.
诺 瞧 他们可没这么糟糕
Nah, see, they ain't so bad.
瞧 人们如果想抽烟的话 他们可以自行决定
See, people can decide for theyselves if they wanna smoke.
真正可恶的是他们公司没有我们的同意却杀死我们
The real evil are them companies killin' us without consent.
孟山都 力拓 大型制药厂 英国石油 哈里伯顿（公司名）
Monsanto. Rio Tinto. Big Pharma, BP, Halliburton.
我读到有一些黑幕被记录了下来
I been readin' there's some dark shit goin' down.
没有一家公司他妈的想雇用我们
Not that any of 'em motherfuckers ever wanna hire us.
但是真正的罪犯 他们是不会关注我们这些小喽啰的
But the real criminals, they don't bother with us small-timers.
现在斯罗文先生将为我们介绍两位态度积极的雇员
And now Mr. Slovin will "Interview" Two "Prospective employees".
在这能学到很多东西
Many lessons to be learned here,
女士们 请高度注意
ladies. Please pay close attention.
嗨 谢谢你能过来
Hello, and thank you for coming in today.
好的 也欢迎你
Well, hello to you, too.
嗨 也谢谢你今天花时间见我
Hello, and thank you so much for taking the time to see me today.
我拥有过最好的老板
The best boss I ever had?
我必须说是厨房的掌管格洛丽亚
I would have to say Gloria in the kitchen right here
因为她真的很有组织能力 而且她能弹奏美妙的音乐
because she's really organized, and she plays real good music.
我最大的优点 我必须说 是我积极的态度
My greatest strength, I'd have to say, is my positive attitude,
和我记忆方面的才能
and my aptitude for rote memorization.
一旦我见过某样东西 我就会记住它
I see something once, and I got it down.
我很有效地使用我的时间 我几乎从不迟到
I use my time very efficiently. I'm almost never late.
她今天都迟到了
She was late today.
举个例子 在我以前那份工作 一个长期客户
For example, in my old job, a long-term client
即将把自己的生意事业给一个竞争者
was about to take his business to a competitor.
我能够与那个客户会面并且
I was able to meet with the
在日常生活中改变了他处理他账目的方式
customer and change the way we handled his account
保住了他的生意
on a day-to-day basis in order to keep the business.
我觉得与你的同事们保持紧密的关系
I think it's important to have close,
是非常重要的
intimate relationships with your co-workers.
这对士气的提高时很有帮助的 你知道吗
It's good for morale, you know?
好吧 这好像是犯规了吧
Okay, that's, like, a foul.
与你们会谈很愉快 谢谢你们
It was lovely meeting both of you, thank you.
谢谢 斯罗文先生 我想说为菲利普莫里斯公司工作
Thank you, Mr. Slovin, and may I say what a privilege it would be
是多么特别的待遇
to work for the Philip Morris Corporation,
自从1983年以来 一家保持着
a company that has remained the largest cigarette manufacturer
全美最大雪茄生产商的公司
in the US since 1983,
加上在过去44年中股息翻了46倍
plus has increased its dividends 46 times in the last 44 years.
你们把这个市场树立起来 全然不顾一个
You all tore this market up in the face of a world
努力想把你们拆毁的世界
that was trying to tear you down.
现在 看吧 我就是为这家公司而生
Now, see, that's the company for me.
-棒 棒 -棒 美味姐
- Yeah! Yeah! - Yeah, Taystee!
谢谢你 杰弗逊小姐
Thank you, Miss Jefferson.
对 对 让我听到为杰弗逊小姐欢呼的掌声
Yeah, yes, let's hear a round of applause for Miss Jefferson,
还有冈萨雷斯小姐
and Miss Gonzales.
--塔莎 塔莎 塔莎
- - Taystee! Taystee! Taystee!
她们需要那张照片 宝贝
They gonna need that picture, boo.
我害怕看到他躺在那里
I'm afraid to see him lying there.
我想一旦你见了他 你就不会再害怕了
I think once you see him, you won't be scared.
他还是我们的RJ 他只是不在那个身躯里面了
He's still our RJ. He's just not in that body anymore.
但是就好像 一旦葬礼结束了
But it's like, once the funeral is over,
他就真的不在了 你知道吗
he's really gone, you know?
没错
Yeah.
我把这个男孩抚养长大
I raised that boy.
看他从牙齿参差不齐到成为少女杀手
Watched that smile go from snaggletooth to lady-killer.
我发誓他可以把鱼儿迷得跳出水面
I swear he could charm the fish out of water.
他们怎么能够逃脱制裁
Man, how can they get away with this?
难道没人可以做些什么吗
Ain't nobody gonna do nothing?
警方声称他携带武器
Cops claim he was armed.
我不知道 可能他是吧 我
I don't know, maybe he was. I...
我告诉他不要带枪
I told him to not carry a piece.
一个黑人男子在晚上行走在这个城市
A black man walking around this city at night...
我们计划一起去看自由女神像
We had plans to go to the Statue of Liberty together.
我们谁也没去过那
Neither of us ever been.
我们都预定好了 走向女神像头部 也预定好了一切
We had reservations to walk up into the head and everything.
真是太愚蠢了
So stupid.
我会带着你
I'll take you.
我懂你的感受 美味妞
I got you now, Taystee Girl.
你不能保证那些
You can't promise that.
我保护我的孩子
I protect my babies.
他已经走了
This one got away,
但是我像你保证 除非我死了 不然我不会让这再发生
but I swear to you, I will die before I see that happen again.
我会保证你安全
I will keep you safe.
来吧 来
Come on, come.
来吧 我懂你的感受
Come on, I've got you.
-还好吗 -怎么样
- Well? - How'd it go in there?
-终于不便秘了 -真棒 真是好样的
- Victory. - Yeah! That's my girl!
你真行 你肯定感觉好多了
Good for you, you must feel so much better.
-我只是感觉到轻松多了 -是酸奶 对吧 妈妈总是知道的
- I just feel free. - It was the yogurt, right? A mother knows.
我给你的饮料帮助了
The drink that I gave you has helped women in my family dookie
我的家族14代人解决拉粑粑的问题
for 14 generations.
你知道 我觉得这只是
You know, I think it was a combination of both things.
不管这是什么 都没关系 我很快乐 你们知道吗
Whatever it was, it don't matter. I am so happy, you guys.
嘿 这里发生了什么事
Hey, what's going on here?
-达亚终于拉出了粑粑了 -好大一坨
- Daya finally shit! - A big one.
她感觉好多了
She feels so much better now.
我的天 我真不敢相信你们这群人
My God! I can't believe you guys!
我从没这样丢脸过 天啊
I've never been so humiliated. Jesus!
行了 继续吧
Well, go on.
去追上她 告诉她一切都会好的
Go after her. Tell her it's gonna be okay.
好吧
Okay.
我们让她难堪了
We embarrassed her.
管它呢 这很常见啊 妈妈让她们的孩子难堪
Whatever, happens, mothers embarrass their kids.
没错
Yeah.
嘿 你他妈的从哪拿到的酸奶
Hey, where the fuck did you get the yogurt?
所以呢 斯罗文先生 谁得到了这份工作
So, Mr. Slovin, who gets the job?
塔莎 杰弗逊小姐
Miss Tasha Jefferson.
太棒了 手下败将 你这个干瘪女
That's right! In your face, Skinny Bean!
无所谓 这没有任何意义
Whatever, it don't even mean nothing.
我甚至都不吸烟
I don't even smoke.
美味姐
Taystee!
好了 关于这份工作 结果已经公正的得出来了
Okay, and that concludes job fair.
谢谢 各位 谢谢
Thank you, everyone. Thank you.
嘿 所以 我该如何联系上某个与这份工作有关的人
Hey, so, how do I get a hold of someone about that job?
你说什么
Excuse me?
一份工作 我听说如果你赢了 你就可以与某个人取得联系
A job. I heard you get hooked up with one if you win this thing.
本身胜出就是一场胜利
Winning is a victory in itself.
但是去年 奥坎普就得到了类似接待员的工作岗位
But last year, Ocampo got set up with some receptionist gig.
那不是真的 这不是一场比赛
That's simply untrue. This isn't a contest.
你做到最好是因为这本来就是你应该做的
You do your best because that's what you're supposed to do.
你怎么就这么难理解呢
Why is it so hard for you people to understand?
你就像个孩子 我的礼物在哪 注意看我
You're like babies. "Where's my present?" "Pay attention to me."
给我那个 把供暖修好 建一个体育馆
"Give me things." "Fix the heat." "Build a gym."
我他妈的不是你妈 长大点好么
I'm not your goddamn mommy. Grow up!
为了答谢你的努力工作和成功
In acknowledgment of your hard work and success,
一份10块钱的奖励会添加到你的杂货店基金 享受吧
an award of $10 will be added to your commissary fund. Enjoy.
棒耶 真不错
Yeah, that's something.
真是不错 谢谢你 菲格罗亚小姐
That is something. Thank you, Miss Figueroa.
噢 不是吧
Oh, shit.